Guide to the Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute AD.RG.024.1
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
NYU Abu Dhabi Institute: Programs and Events
2007-2020
2008-2015
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
AD.RG.024.1
7 Linear Feet in 2 legal size document boxes; 1 OS Flat File; 3 [16x20] OS boxes of 343 DVDs; 157 USB flash drives
157 Items [individual USB drives]
14 Terabytes of recorded programs and conferences, and digital publications
The collection "Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute: Public Program Materials" documents over ten years' worth of events that took place at the Institute from 2007, with the majority of the contents covering the years 2008 through 2015. This body of material from the Institute's first decade is relevant to anyone researching the early years of NYU Abu Dhabi as a way to understand the University's regional and global role in advancing research and scholarship, and exchanging knowledge collaboratively with the wider public. Audiovisual recordings of programs, conferences, and performances serves as a valuable collection of research knowledge.
Scope and Contents
The collection "Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute: Public Program Materials" documents over ten years' worth of events that took place at the Institute from 2007-2008, with the majority of the contents covering the years 2008 through 2015. This body of material from the Institute's first decade will be of interest to anyone researching the early years of NYU Abu Dhabi as a way to understand the University's regional and global role in advancing research and scholarship, and exchanging knowledge collaboratively with the wider public.
Materials include printed calendars; promotional cards, flyers, and brochures; a small collection of printed photographic materials; published "Year in Review" yearbooks; anniversary commemorative booklets, and significantly, a series of audiovisual files (photos, videos, slide presentations) from over 300 events sponsored by the Institute from 2007-2015, documenting the earliest popular events, conferences, and performances.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The initial three increments of the physical collection were transferred to the University Archives in March 2019. In 2024, the archivist was granted access to two servers containing the digital collection of audiovisual events (approx. 14 TB of digital files).
Arrangement
RG 24-1 is arranged into five series. 1. Calendars, Promotional Materials, and Program Brochures, 2008-2018. 2. Photographic Materials: Prints and Contact Sheets [ca. 2008-2013]. 3. NYUAD Institute Yearbooks, 2008-2019. 4. Anniversary Commemorative Books. And 5. Audiovisual event and program files, 2007-2015. Materials are arranged chronologically in each series by date of event.
Biographical / Historical
New York University, in developing a new "Global Network" of degree granting campuses and academic centers across six continents (NYU New York, NYU Abu Dhabi, and NYU Shanghai), established the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute in 2008, two years prior to the Abu Dhabi campus opening its doors to its first class of students and faculty. The Institute was the first "on-the-ground" operation of the University in the UAE. As a research outreach and sponsorship component, it was established to create and support innovative research programs, organize public discussions with experts from around the world, and invite participation not only from and for the NYU network constituency but also from and for local, regional, and national communities.
The Institute's inaugural program in October 2008, "On the Art of the Novel," featured renowned Lebanese novelist Elias Khoury. Its "first collaboration" came during the November 2008 program "Stephen Hawking's 'A Briefer History of Time'," featuring the Arabic translation of that book by Kalima, the translation initiative launched by Abu Dhabi Authority for Culture and Heritage (ADACH). In December of 2008, "Neurolinguistics and Imaging: Progress and Prospects" was the first multi-day program that the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute sponsored. Early events took place at the Al Mamoura Auditorium in Abu Dhabi.
NYU Abu Dhabi Institute programming was early-on a joint effort between faculty and administration in Abu Dhabi, and faculty and administrative leadership in New York. The Institute created an Advisory Committee that also first convened in Decmeber 2008, and in May of 2009, the NYUAD offices at 19 Washington Square North sponsored the first New York-hosted Institute event, a lecture titled "Building Big: A Critical Examination of the Planning of Mega Urban Transportation." The Institute continues to organize programs in both Abu Dhabi and New York. When the NYU Abu Dhabi downtown campus was built and finally available as a venue for programs, the Institute hosted its first on-campus lecture there in December 2009, "The Predictioneer's Game," a talk about game theory with NYU Professor Bruce Bueno de Mesquita. Student-centered Institute programming was introduced in 2011 with the "Hackathon for Social Good in the Arab World."
Today, the NYUAD Institute continues to sponsor and support multi-day conferences, workshops and seminars relevant to the NYUAD curriculum and areas of research, across a range of subjects from falconry to poetry to genomics to youth unemployment crises. The Institute has become an important asset of the university that seeks to deepen understanding of the world, generate important new knowledge, and facilitate breakthrough discoveries in science and technology.
References and for further information: "10 Years: Celebrating the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute"
Related Materials
Administrative and Program Event Files have been processed as RG-24-2. These records are restricted following the 20-year restriction policy for university administrative records.
Research institutes; Universities and Colleges -- institutes; Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates; NYU Abu Dhabi
- Calendars, Promotional Materials and Program Brochures, 2008-2014
  Scope and Contents
  A collection of printed materials that were displayed, distributed and mailed as invitations, covering the years 2008-2014.
  - Institute Event Calendar/Brochure Prep Notes, Fall 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Preliminary Program Schedule, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Institute Event Calendars, 2008-2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Washington Square Institute Event Calendars, 2012-2013 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Institute Event Invitation Announcement Cards, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Institute Event Posters (oversize), Fall 2009 (Map-case 1.C)
  - Institute Event Announcements/Posters, Spring 2010 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Institute Event Program Brochures [incomplete set], 2009-2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Program: Embracing Sports in the UAE, November 19-20, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Jointly sponsored by NYUAD Institute, Abu Dhabi Sports Council, and NYU School of Professional Studies, Sports and Society
  - Press Kit, February 2008-February 2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographic Materials: Photo prints and Contact Sheets, [ca. 2008 - 2013]
  This is a small series that separates out some of the printed photographs and contact sheets from early events that were transferred with records to the University Archives (users should note that the majority of event photos are digital, and have been preserved as part of the Audiovisual Event Files series).
  - Photographs, January 2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photo Contact Sheets: Brain Imaging, January 14, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photo Contact Sheets: Search for Social Entrepreneurship, January 18, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Photo Contact Sheets: Education, Media, and Human Development, January 20, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- NYUAD Institute Yearbooks, 2010 -
  The NYUAD Institute publishes an annual "Year in Review," a yearbook highlighting major events throughout the year. This series includes selected print copies of the publication, as well as E-book versions.
  Note: copies of the NYUAD Institute Year in Review are also in the NYUAD Publications and Ephemera Collection (AD-RG-2).
  Preservica Public URL
  View content in Preservica
  - Year In Review, 2010-2011 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Yearbook, 2010-2011 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Year In Review, 2011-2012 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Yearbook, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Year In Review, 2012-2013 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year In Review, 2013-2014 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year In Review, 2014-2015 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year In Review, 2015-2016 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2015-2016 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Year in Review, 2016-2017 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2016-2017 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Year In Review, 2017-2018 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2017-2018 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Year In Review, 2018-2019 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2018-2019 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Year In Review, 2019-2020 (Box E-records, Folder Institute Year Books)
  - Year in Review, 2020-2021 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Year in Review, 2022-2023 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Anniversary Commemorative Yearbooks/Publications, 2013; 2018
  - Five Years: Celebrating the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 10 Years: Celebrating 10 Years of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Audiovisual Event Files (Conferences and Programs), 2007-2015
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  NYU Abu Dhabi Institute staff arranged for the photography and video recording of most Institute events. Many of the recordings have been curated and shared on the Institute's YouTube Channel. Records in this series constitute the full packaged files from various lectures, workshops and conferences, and are organized by date of event. Records are primarily audiovisual, and include digital photos, video footage, and in some cases, copies of slide presentations from events 2008 - 2015. Archivists continue to partner with NYUAD Institute staff for the ongoing transfer of inactive materials.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual materials have been minimally processed. The container list below provides a basic inventory of contents. Files are viewable onsite by appointment.
  - AY 2008-2009
    - SIPEX - Sea Ice Physics & Ecology Experiment, Oct. 17, 2007 (Box E-records)
      View audiovisual content in Preservica
    - NYUAD Institute Event Photos, Fall 2008 (Box E-records)
    - On the Art of the Novel, Oct. 7, 2008 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Elias Khoury
    - Banking the World, Nov 10, 2008 (Box E-records)
      Program Speaker/Officiator: Jonathan Morduch
    - Stephen Hawking's A Briefer History of Time [2 copies], Nov. 12, 2008 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Glennys Farrar
    - America's Elections 2008, Nov. 16, 2008 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Hassan Fattah; Bob Shrum; Rogan Kersh
    - Outside the Box Alternate Modernities, Nov 18, 2008 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Edward J. Sullivan
    - Kluge: the Haphazard Construction of the Human Mind, Dec. 15, 2008 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Gary Marcus
    - Edward Said's The World, The Text, and the Critic: A Discussion on Edward Said, A Conversation with Marina Warner, Dec. 17, 2008 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Marina Warner
    - Brain Imaging, Jan. 14, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Heeger
    - The Search for Social Entrepreneurship, Jan. 18, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Paul C. Light
    - Education, Media, and Human Development, Jan. 20-22, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: James Fraser
    - In the Public Eye: Media and Civil Society in the Arab World, Jan. 22, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Hussein Amin; Nabil Khatib; Rami Khouri; Martin Newland; Lawrence Pintak; Zayani Mohamed
    - Eisenstein's Film Forum, Feb. 12, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mikhail Iampolski; Richard Allen
    - Africa Arab Gulf Relationships, Mar. 03-04, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Yaw Nyarko
    - The Two Europes, Apr. 15, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Levering Lewis
    - On Arabian Oral Poetry and Tribal Lore, Apr. 26, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Saad Abdalla Sowayan; Bernard Haykel; Philip F. Kennedy
    - Climate Change: Financing Green Development, May 03-05, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Richard Stewart; Bernard Haykel
  - AY 2009-2010
    - Islamic Art and Architecture: Christian Images in Islamic Art, Sep. 29, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Yasser Tabbaa
    - Le Corbusier's Toward an Architecture, in Conjuction with Kalima, Oct. 1, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jean-Louis Cohen
    - Completing the Circuit: Formula 1, Yas Island, Oct. 15, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Khaldoon Al Mubarak; Falah Al Ahbabi; Richard Cregan; Victor Matheson
    - Cosmpolitanism, Multiculturalism, Oct. 21, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Cyrus R.K. Patell
    - The Conservation of Islamic Heritage and Architecture in Cairo and the UAE, Nov. 11, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Peter Sheehan; Nicholas Warner
    - CO2 Rising: The World's Greatest Challenge, Nov. 15, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tyler Volk; Anne Rademacher
    - Mapping the Ancient World, Nov. 22, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Rita Wright
    - Teaching the Ancient World, Nov. 23, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Andrew Monson; Walter Scheidel
    - Higher Education in the Global Age, Dec. 6-7, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Al Bloom; Marit Westermann
    - The Predictioneer's Game, Dec. 9, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Bruce Bueno de Mesquita
    - Writers in Conversation with Arabian Nights, Dec. 15, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Philip Kennedy; Marina Warner
    - The Arabian Nights, Dec. 15-17, 2009 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Marina Warner; Karl Sabbagh
    - The Eighth Day of Creation, Jan. 6, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David A. Scicchitano; Gloria Coruzzi
    - Genomics and Systems Biology, Jan. 6-7, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David A. Scicchitano; Gloria Coruzzi; etc
    - Future Horizons of Fundamental Physics, Jan. 11-14, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Marit Westermann; David Spergel
    - Hubble Trouble: The Expanding Universe and Dark Energy Enigma, Jan. 14, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Georgi Dvali
    - Matters of Taste, Jan. 17, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Charles Spence; Barry C. Smith
    - Strategic Issues Facing the Port of New York and Dubai, Jan. 24, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Asaf Ashar
    - Islamic Art in the Gulf Region [2 copies], Jan. 28, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jochen Sokoly
    - Emerging Powers, Global Security, and the Middle East, Feb. 8-10, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Dr. Stephen Krasner; Strobe Talbott
    - Abu Dhabi as a Leadership City, Feb. 09, 2010 (Box E-records)
    - Leadership for a New Era, Feb. 16, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Fadi Ghandour, Barbara Ibrahim
    - Texts and Textiles, Feb. 18, 2010 (Box E-records)
    - Islamic Art and Architecture, Feb. 18-21, 2010 (Box E-records)
    - Visual Reflections on Arabic Poetry, Feb 21, 2010 (Box E-records)
    - Africa and the Indian Ocean, Mar. 14-16, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Yaw Nyarko, Bernard Haykel
    - The Magic of Words, Mar. 28, 2010 (Box E-records)
    - Parviz Tanavoli: A Life's Journey, Mar. 30, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers:Parvis Tanavoli
    - The Collection and Display of Islamic Art, Mar. 31, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Priscilla Soucek; Haidar Navina
    - Library of Arabic Liturature, Apr. 6, 2010 (Box E-records)
    - Memorandum Signing, April 6, 2010 (Box E-records)
    - A Tale of Two Cities and of Climate Change, Apr. 11, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Holland
    - Beyond Child Indicators, Apr. 13, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Hirokazu Yoshikawa, Pia Britto
    - Art Museums Here and Now, Apr. 18-19, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Zaki Nusseibeh, Hilary Ballon
    - Museums Tomorrow, Apr. 18, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Neil MacGregor; Kavita Singh; John Onians
    - Forces Moulding Mega Urban Transportation Projects, Apr. 20, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Harry T. Dimitriou
    - Common Challenges Uncommon Cities, Apr. 20, 2010 (Box E-records)
    - A Brief History of Arab Music, May. 5, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mustafa Said
    - The Relevance and Irrelevance of Muslim Political Traditions, May 9, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Aziz Al-Azmeh
    - From the World Wide Web to the World Wide Computer, May 11, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Keith Ross
  - AY 2010-2011
    - Global Finance After the Crisis, Sept. 16, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ingo Walter
    - From Metaphor to Model: What Victorians Understood About Markets That Modern Economists Often Miss, Sept. 26, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mary Poovey
    - Interdisciplinary Studies in Information Security and Privacy, Oct. 3-4, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Nasir Memon, William Hery
    - Understanding Privacy in Context, Oct. 4, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Helen Nissenbaum; Mireille Hildebrandt
    - The Future is Now: Making Art/Thinking Ecology, Oct. 10, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Marina Zurkow
    - The Ethical Brain, Oct. 20, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Micheal Gazzaniga
    - Global Cost-Benefit Analysis: Challenges and Opportunities, Oct. 26, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Michael A. Livermore; Richard L. Revesz.
    - The Use of Economics on Environmental and Public Health Policy, Oct. 27, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Richard L. Revesz; Oliver Harrison
    - The Cosmopolitans, Nov. 01, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Zubin Shroff, Joanne Savio
    - Interpreting the 1001 Nights for the Stage, Nov. 4, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tim Supple, Stage Director; Houda Echouafani, Lassen Razzougui, Ramzi Choukair, Artists
    - Situating Sustainability, Nov. 8, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Anne Rademacher
    - Realizing the Ecological City, Nov. 08, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mary Candenasso; Julie Sze
    - The Science and Pseudoscience of Winning Elections, Nov. 14, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Donald Green
    - Leadership for a New Era: Fostering Leadership for Public Well-Being, Nov. 16, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Fadi Ghandour; Barbara Ibrahim; Asya Al-Lamki
    - In Defense of Politics, Nov. 21, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Steven Smith
    - Galileo's Finger: The Ten Great Ideas of Science, Nov. 24, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Peter Atkins; Joel Bernstein
    - Nationalization of the Workforce in the GCC Countries, Nov. 27, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Samira Al. Atallah
    - The US and Iran: Is Diplomacy Possible?, Dec. 8, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Reza Aslan
    - Obama's Foreign Policy, Dec. 12, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: James Traub; Hassan Fattah
    - Emerging Challenges and Opportunities in the Gulf, Dec. 15, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: William Rugh
    - The US, Iran and the Gulf: Regional Contexts and Transnational Currents, Dec. 15-16, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Farhad Kazemi, Ali Banuazizi, Augustus Richard Norton
    - Musician Scholars of the Middle East, Dec. 20-21, 2010 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Walter Zev Feldman, Dariush Talai, A.J. Racy, Munir Nurettin Beken
    - Understanding Social Entrepreneurship in a Time of Urgent Threats, Jan. 6, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - Supercomputing the Imperative and the Path Forward, Jan. 9-10, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Paul Horn, Ralph Roskies, Mark Tuckerman
    - The Data and Computer-Driven Transformation, Jan. 9, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Harry Edward Seidel
    - The Evolution of Death, Jan. 12, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tyler Volk
    - The (Unfortunate) Complexity of Economic Systems, Jan. 16, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jean-Philippe Bouchaud
    - Probability Theory, Statistical Physics and Applications, Jan. 16, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Gerard Ben Arous, Federico Camia, Charles Newman
    - Non-Polygonal Image Shapes, Jan. 17, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - Climate Change and the Mathematics of Sea Ice, Jan. 19, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Kenneth M. Golden
    - Collaborative Workshop on Climate Finance, Jan. 22-23, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Robert Bradley, Richard Stewart
    - Gardens of Eden, History, and the Human Imagination, Jan. 23, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Marit Westermann
    - Arab Voices, Jan. 24, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: James Zogby
    - Middle Eastern Comics and their Place in the 21st Century, Jan. 25, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Dez Skinn, Qais Sedki, Charles Kochman
    - Trends in Air Transportation, Implications for Abu Dhabi and New York, Jan. 30, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: R. John Hansman
    - The Life and Afterlife of Indian Images: How Early 20th Century Archaeology and Conservation Transformed Ancient Indian Bronze Icons, Feb. 7, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sanchita Balachandran
    - The Interface Between Field Archaeology and Conservation, Feb. 7-9, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Hannelore Roemich, Norbert Baer
    - Political Currents in Egypt and the Middle East, Feb. 10, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tarik Yousef; Shadi Hamid; Nasr Arif; Riaz Hassan
    - NYU DTC (1): Lessons from Beyond Vision, Feb. 13, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - NYU DTC (2): Are the Actions and Emotions of Music "Out There"?, Feb. 13, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - The Science of Sad Sounds, Feb. 13, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Huron
    - The Nature of Taste, Feb. 13-14, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Paul Boghossian
    - Magical Arbitrariness, Feb. 14, 2011 (Box E-records)
    - Repositioning Islam Through the 99, Feb. 21, 2011 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Naif Al-Mutawa
    - Beyond the Crash: Overcoming the First Crisis of Globalisation, Feb. 24, 2011 (Box E-records)